"Don’t Eat Raw Alfalfa Sprouts"
According to the U.S. Centers
for Disease Control
and Prevention,
we should cook alfalfa sprouts,
because eating raw sprouts
can lead to salmonella
food poisoning.
It's especially important
not to eat raw sprouts
if you are particularly old
or young,
immunosuppressed, or pregnant.
How serious of an issue
is this?
Over the last few decades,
at least 2,700 Americans
have been sickened by sprouts.
That's more than
a hundred people a year.
Of course,
during that same time,
more than a hundred thousand
Americans
were being food poisoned
by eggs
contaminated with Salmonella.
Indeed, Salmonella in eggs
is a national epidemic
in the United States.
Salmonella is a gift
that can keep on giving,
triggering arthritis sometimes,
which, in rare cases,
can last a lifetime.
So, no sprouts
on that sandwich,
but do you hear the CDC
saying no eggs,
even though they cause
a thousand times more illness?
No, but the CDC does say
no raw or runny eggs,
no soft-boiled eggs,
no sunny side up.
Even the egg industry itself
admits that over-easy,
poached, sunny side up,
or soft-boiled eggs
can't be considered safe.
No wonder eggs are sickening
100,000 Americans a year.
Eggs have to be cooked hard
to kill off their bacteria.
Similarly, if we boiled
our sprouts,
they would be safe, too,
but no one wants
to do that either.
The largest national sampling
was from about a decade ago,
when the Food and Drug
Administration tested sprouts
and sprout facilities
from all over
the United States.
The agency found that 1 percent
of alfalfa sprout samples
were affected, and even worse,
ten percent of alfalfa sprout
seed samples were, too.
So, that's why you can't
just grow them yourself.
The bacteria can get
into the nooks and crannies
of the alfalfa seed itself.
The majority of outbreaks
have been linked to alfalfa,
but there' also been outbreaks
tied to clover sprouts,
mung bean sprouts
(which are more like
typical bean sprouts),
and sprouted chia.
The national FDA survey
did not find any salmonella
in mung bean sprouts,
but did find
that about two percent
were contaminated
with Listeria,
which can be a particularly
devastating infection
for pregnant women.
What about the deadly
Jack in the Box
E. coli O157:H7?
How often can it be found
in retail ground beef,
sprouts, and mushrooms?
Well, none were found
in any mushrooms,
but 1 out of every 90
or so samples of burger meat
was contaminated,
and about 1 out of just 70
sprout containers.
But what if you really like
raw sprouts?
Instead of alfalfa,
use broccoli sprouts.
They have smooth seeds,
and after testing
the equivalent
of about five million packages,
less than one in a thousand
bulk samples
turned up positive
and that may have been
contamination
from other types of sprouts.
Broccoli sprouts
are easy and cheap
to make on your own
kitchen counter,
like I do
for pennies a serving.
I have more than a dozen videos
on all the amazing things
the sulforaphane
in broccoli sprouts can do,
everything from treating
autism spectrum disorder
to detoxifying the effects
of air pollution.
They've also been shown
to combat
different types
of cancer cells.
And you can pretty much
only get
this natural
immune system enhancer
in cruciferous vegetables
like broccoli,
broccoli sprouts,
and I guess
if you're really desperate,
broccoli beer.